Tom Husband

Full stack engineer

🔼 thusbandUK@gmail.com 📞 07789246378 🙎 Bristol \delta British

=== 9-2-79

thusbandUK

Portfolio: https://thusbanduk.github.io/portfolio/

Summary

Quick learner who forms strong, positive relationships with colleagues and clients. Proven ability to communicate complex ideas in a digestible format. Looking to specialise in coding following more than a decade of working as a chemistry teacher.



Technical Skills

- < Javascript />
- < CSS />
- < HTML/>
- < React / Redux />
- < PostgreSQL/>
- < Node.js / Express />



Certificate

Full Stack Engineering Codecademy

Online course introducing principles of web design. Skills covered: CSS, HTML, Javascript, testing, asynchronous functions, the React and Redux Frameworks, Node.js, Express, Passport, PostgreSQL and principles of database management, web security, common algorithms, data structures, connecting front end to back end.

Work experience

- Chingu Back end developer May 2023 – Jun 2023 / Online
 - ☐ Used Agile methodology to produce the first iteration of a new app
 - ☐ Built the back end of the app, which will allow users to save encrypted journals
 - ☐ Used dependencies including Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL and Passport to connect front end with database, including authentication of users
- Freelance Web developer Sep 2022 - Apr 2023 / Bristol
 - ☐ Built a website for children's book author Sarah Lavelle - https://sarahlavelle.co.uk
 - Responsive website introduces the author and features downloadable resources
 - ☐ Configured with Google Analytics, cookie consent banner and compliant with GDPR legislation
- Freelance Web developer Oct 2022 - Feb 2023 / Bristol
 - ☐ Built a website for a local artisan who makes picture frames https://ravenframes.co.uk
 - Responsive website showcases work and publishes contact information



Education

University of Cambridge - MEd Education in Science Oct 2012 - Jul 2013

> Critical evaluation of academic literature, culminating in the design and implementation of a research project.

University of Sheffield – BSc Chemistry Oct 1998 - Jul 2001

> Batchelor's degree in chemistry, including laboratory work and theories of organic, inorganic and physical chemistry.

Key skills

Teacher

- ☐ Planning and delivering lessons
- Providing feedback
- ☐ Motivating students
- ☐ Explaining complicated ideas
- ☐ Pastoral care of students
- ☐ Promoting well-being

Examiner

- ☐ Carefully reading scripts
- ☐ Critically evaluating answers
- ☐ Checking for subtle details that may improve or prejudice an answer
- ☐ Identifying and rewarding alternative approaches

Science writer

- ☐ Identifying intriguing examples of everyday science to describe
- Researching the underlying science
- ☐ Producing accurate copy
- ☐ Responding to feedback from editors
- ☐ Explaining complex ideas in an engaging, clear way

Publications

- ☐ The Sweet Science of Candy
 Making, 2014, ChemMatters,
 Washington, ACS,
 http://bit.ly/1HltVdm
- ☐ Polished Polymers, 2015, The Mole, Cambridge, RSC, https://bit.ly/3MCjGIK
- ☐ Chocolate's Champion Chompability, 2013, The Mole, Cambridge, RSC, https://rsc.li/41S9D6R



Further work experience

Freelance

Jun 2018 to present

- □ Chemistry tutoring for GCSE and A-level students□ Marking public A-level chemistry exams, 2018,
 - 2019, 2022, 2023, OCR A exam board
- ☐ Science writing for educational text books, publishers including Oxford University Press, Cambridge University Press

Teaching

QT Education agency, Portishead

Aug 2018 to Jul 2020

Second in Science, Norton Hill School, Midsomer Norton *Aug 2017 to Jul 2018*

Science Leader, Christ's College Finchley, London *Aug 2016 to Jul 2017*

Chemistry teacher, CATS College, London *Aug 2014 to Jul 2016*

Chemistry teacher, Hendon School, Barnet, London *Aug 2011 to Jul 2014*

English teacher, Australia Pacific College, Sydney, Australia *Aug 2008 to Aug 2009*

English teacher, University of International Business and Economics, Beijing *Aug 2006 to Jan 2008*

English teacher, Beijing International Studies University, Beijing Aug 2005 to Jul 2006

Other information

Worked as a news reporter, Southern Daily Echo, Southampton Sep 2002 to Jan 2005

Backpacking in Asia

Aug 2008 – Aug 2009

Long term ambition

To build a website / app that helps students learn chemistry in a fun and engaging way.